bitlyenterprise.com 2017-12-31

# Bitly | Privacy Policy

Effective Date: 11/01/2017

This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of Bitly, Inc. ("Bitly", "we" or "us") on the collection, use, security and disclosure of information about you on [https://bitly.com](https://bitly.com/) (the "Site") and the services, features, content or applications offered by Bitly (collectively with the Site, the "Services"). It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. Bitly receives information about you from various sources, such as: (i) when you register for the Site and the Services, through your user account with Bitly (your "Account"); (ii) when you use the Services; and (iii) from third party websites and services. When you use the Services, you are consenting to the collection, transfer, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. The information you provide may be transferred, processed and/or accessed by us in the United States or another country where we (or our service providers) operate.

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield

Bitly, Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework's applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield List. [[https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)]

Bitly, Inc. is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Bitly, Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Bitly, Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

### What Does This Privacy Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy covers the treatment of the information gathered by Bitly when you use or access the Services. This Privacy Policy also covers Bitly's treatment of any information about you that Bitly's business partners share with Bitly or that Bitly shares with its business partners.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of other businesses that Bitly does not own or control, including other companies' websites, services and applications ("Third Party Services") that you can access through the Services, such as Facebook or Twitter, or to individuals that Bitly does not manage or employ. While we attempt to partner with only those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access.

### What Information Does Bitly Collect and How is it Used?

The information we collect is primarily used to provide the Services, to process and complete any transactions, to respond to inquiries, to personalize and improve the Services, to monitor and analyze usage and trends of the Services, and to allow our business partners to understand how you interact with our Services, as described in this Policy. In connection with certain aspects of the Services, we may request, collect and/or display some information about you. We collect the following types of information from our users.

#### Registered User Information:

When you create an Account, we will collect personal information from you, such as your name and email address. If you create an Account using your login from another account, such as Facebook or Twitter, we will acess and collect the personal information about you that the account provides (which is based on your privacy settings), so that you can create your Account with us. We use your contact information to send you information about our Services. You may unsubscribe from receiving certain types of these messages through your Account settings, although Bitly reserves the right to contact you when we believe it is necessary, such as for administrative and account management purposes.

_Note regarding children:_ We do not knowingly collect personal information from children. If we learn that we have collected personal information of a child under 13, we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible

#### URL Information:

One feature of the Services is the ability to create shortened uniform resource locators (URLs) of websites ("Bitly Links"). When you create a Bitly Link, Bitly collects and stores both the original URL and the shortened URL and, if you are logged in to your Account, we will associate that information with your Account. Bitly also collects and stores your IP address and the time and date on which you shortened the original URL and when you share the Bitly Link and information on the channels through which the Bitly Link was shared.

#### Metrics and Analytics:

Bitly collects information about accesses (such as clicks) of every Bitly Link created through the Services. This information includes, but is not limited to: (i) the IP address and physical location of the devices accessing the Bitly Link; (ii) the referring websites or services; (iii) the time and date of each access; and (iv) information about sharing of the Bitly Link on Third Party Services such as Twitter and Facebook. This information is used by Bitly and its partners to improve their websites and services by, for example, providing value-added features, and to analyze clicks on Bitly Links, for example to understand how, when and where Bitly Links are clicked.

#### User Content:

Some features of the Services allow you to provide content to the Services, such as written descriptions of URLs, comments, images and video. For example, using the Bundles feature, Bitly users can curate and "bundle together" a set of links, and can add content to those Bundles, such as comments and videos. All content submitted by you to the Services may be retained by Bitly, even after you terminate your account, and may continue to be shared by third parties, as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Information Collected From Third Party Services:

Some features of the Services allow you to share your content and Bitly Links through your accounts with other companies such as Facebook and Twitter. If you choose to connect Bitly to such Third Party Services, we may collect information related to your use of those Third Party Services, such as authentication tokens that allow us to connect to your Third Party Service accounts. We will ask you for permission before you authorize our collection of this information. We will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. We may also collect information about how you are using the Services to interact with those connected Third Party Services. Note that Third Party Services may have the ability to restrict the information that is provided to us based on your privacy settings of that account.

#### Information Collected Automatically:

  * Bitly automatically receives and records information from your web browser when you interact with the Services (including creating or clicking on Bitly Links), such as your IP address, browser type, your general location and cookie information. This information may be used to help us understand how users transit a website, to fight spam/malware, to facilitate collection of data concerning your interaction with the Services (e.g., what Bitly Links you have clicked on) and for other similar purposes.
  * Bitly also automatically receives and records information that your mobile device transmits when you access the Services, like a device identifier, device settings, and operating system. This information is used to facilitate your access and use of the Services, to access and use other Third Party Services, and for other similar purposes.
  * Generally, the Services automatically collect Site usage information, such as the number and frequency of visitors to the Site. Bitly may use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure. This type of aggregate data enables us and third parties authorized by us to figure out how often individuals use parts of the Site so that we can analyze and improve them.
  * We will collect information about your general location (such as your city and state, which is derived from your IP address) when you visit the Site or use the Services, such as by clicking a Bitly Link and we may use various technologies to determine your location (if you enable this feature), when you access and use the Services through a mobile device.
  * We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. We use this confirmation to improve our customer service.

#### Cookie Policy:

Bitly and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

  * Cookies are pieces of text that may be provided to your computer through your web browser when you access a website. Your browser stores cookies in a manner associated with each website you visit. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you visit our Site and use the Services through the web.
  * Bitly cookies also allow Bitly to track when you have clicked on a Bitly Link. Each click of a Bitly Link is tracked using a unique identifier assigned to you in one or more cookies stored by your web browser and associated with Bitly. We may associate the unique identifier in our cookies with the other information we automatically collect when you use the Services, as described above, including your IP address, Bitly Links you click, Bitly Links you create, and information with your Account if you have one.
  * Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. If you disable cookies, you will not be able to use some features of the Services. Bitly cookies are set to automatically expire after 6 months from when they are set.
  * You may also ask Bitly not to place cookies on your web browser. When cookies are disabled in this manner, clicks on Bitly Links are not tied back to or associated with your web browser. However, we will still automatically collect the IP addresses of computers or mobile devices that click on or create Bitly Links.
  * You can also manage other companies’ cookies used for online advertising here: [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)
  * We partner with third parties to track utilization and behavior on our websites, display advertising on our websites, and to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).
  * This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Bitly only and does not cover the use of cookies by any Third Party Services. Bitly does not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer, such as when you visit the website from a Bitly Link.

### What Information Is Shared?

The Services are designed to help you share information with others. As a result, much of the information generated through the Services is shared publicly or with third parties.

We may share the information we collect as described in this policy with third-party business partners, for instance, for the purpose of enhancing our products and services, so that they can market their products or services to you, or so that they may analyze trends about the creation of, and clicks on, Bitly Links. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [support@bitly.com](mailto:support@bitly.com).

#### Bitly Links and Usage Information:

Much of your activity on and through the Services is public by default. This includes, but is not limited to:

  * The original URLs you have shortened, their corresponding Bitly Links, the time and date those URLs were shortened, and metrics and analytics information for your Bitly Links, as described above;
  * Information about what Bitly Links you have clicked on and associated metrics and analytics information, as described above; and
  * Any Bundles you have created, along with content added to those Bundles, if you have elected to make those Bundles public.

Registered users may have some of this information associated with their Accounts. Unregistered users will not have this association, but, as described above, Bitly collects and stores information concerning their use of the Services (such as what Bitly Links they click on, when they clicked, the IP address of their computers when they clicked, etc.) through the use of cookies and automatically collected information.

For registered users, some of this information is publicly accessible through a unique URL, which you can make non-public through your Account settings when you are logged in. Removing access to the unique URL does not, however, make this information non-public, and it may still be accessible through other means, such as Bitly's API services.

Please also remember that if you choose to provide information about yourself using certain features of the Services, then that information is governed by the privacy settings of those particular features and may be publicly available to others.

#### IP Address Information:

While we collect and store IP address information, that information is not shared publicly. As described above, we may share IP address information we collect when you create or click a Bitly Link with our business partners, service providers and other organizations with whom we conduct business for the purposes described in this policy.

#### Information You Elect to Share:

When creating a Bitly Link, you can share that Bitly Link through Third Party Services. Any information that you elect to distribute through Third Party Services is provided to them and may then become accessible to users of those services. You can also access other Third Party Services through the Services, for example by clicking on links in the Statistics page for a Bitly Link. We recommend that you review the terms of services and privacy policies of such Third Party Services that you access through the Services, since Bitly does not control and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Services.

To opt out from having information about your clicks on Bitly Links shared with our business partners, please opt-out using the link provided on this page.

#### User Profile Information:

User profile information including your username, Twitter handle and Facebook account name (to the extent you have linked your Account with those services), and other information you enter may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services. Users' email addresses will not be directly revealed to other users by Bitly.

#### Information Shared with Service Providers of Bitly:

We may employ and contract with third parties to perform certain tasks on our behalf and under our direction (our "Service Providers"). We may need to share information about you with our Service Providers in order to provide our product with research and analytics on user behavior and to provide advertising products and services to users, and email marketing and support services. Unless we tell you differently, our Service Providers do not have any right to use the information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients.

#### Information Disclosed Pursuant to Business Transfers:

We may transfer and/or provide information about our users in connection with an acquisition, sale of company assets, or other situation where user information would be transferred as one of our business assets. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information.

In such a case, the acquirer of Bitly may continue to use your information as set forth in this policy.

#### Information Disclosed for the Protection of Bitly and Others:

Bitly may access, read, preserve, and disclose any information it collects when it has a good faith belief that doing so is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with a law, regulation, or compulsory legal request, including process from a governmental law enforcement or national security agency (ii) enforce these Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof, (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect the rights, property or safety of Bitly, its users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

#### Information We Share With Your Consent:

We will share information about you when you instruct us to do so, such as when you share Bitly Links or content with others through the Services or if we notify you that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information (like sharing/posting it with a Third Party Service).

### How Is My Information Protected?

Your Account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You can prevent unauthorized access to your account by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

Bitly endeavors to protect the information it collects about its users using industry-standard security processes and controls, however, despite these efforts, no security measure is perfect or impenetrable and Bitly does not guarantee or warrant that such measures will prevent unauthorized access to the information about you that is stored by Bitly. In the event we experience a breach of security, we will promptly notify you if your personal information has been compromised, in accordance with applicable law. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [support@bitly.com](mailto:support@bitly.com).

### What Choices Do I Have and What Information of Mine Can I Access?

You don't need an account to create Bitly Links and you can use many of the features of the Services without registering, thereby limiting the type of information that is collected about you individually.

Upon request, Bitly will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. In order to identify you, we may need to request additional information from you in order to respond to your request. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your account or contacting us at [support@bitly.com](mailto:support@bitly.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

Bitly acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Bitly has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the Bitly's Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

If you are a registered user, you can access information associated with your Account by logging into the Site. This information includes a history of the URLs you have shortened, and access to the metrics pages for those URLs. You can deactivate your Account at any time through your Account settings page. If you deactivate your Account, you will no longer be able to access or use the Services.

Please note that in the interest of ensuring that existing Bitly Links continue to function for all of our users, the Bitly Links that you have created and shared cannot be deleted or disabled (even if your Account is deactivated), and any shortening and sharing activity that has already occurred on your Account also cannot be deleted (but your user history can be set to private from within your Account settings). If you have concerns about any unauthorized usage of your Account, please contact us at [support@bitly.com](mailto:support@bitly.com) and we will disable future shortening activity on your Account.

If you are not a registered user, you can access the metrics pages for your Bitly Links by adding the "+" symbol to the end of the URL.

### What Happens When There Are Changes to this Privacy Policy?

Bitly may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make material changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Services or sending you an email and we will indicate when those changes will become effective. You are agreeing to be bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the Services after those changes become effective.

### What If I Have Questions or Concerns?

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy using the Services, please send us a detailed message to: [support@bitly.com](mailto:support@bitly.com). We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.
